Finding Aid for Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.) Records, ca. 1855-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographic Material, circa 1855-2004
  - Display Photographs, 1855-1995
    - People
      - "Chief Justice Warren Burger in Grand Hotel...,", August 18, 1978 (Box 16)
        (no. 15b)
      - George Bush and John Engler at Grand Hotel, 2 prints (Box 16)
        (includes photograph of Bush and Engler with Musser family)
        (nos. 16-17)
      - Portrait of James R. Hayes (Box 16)
        (scanned print only, original returned to Grand Hotel)
        (no. 35)
      - Old porch scene small (Box 16)
        (no. 102)
      - Alben Barkley visit:
        - W. Stewart Woodfill with G. Mennen Williams and Barkley (Box 16)
          (no. 106a)
        - Prentiss Brown, G. Mennen Williams, Barkley (Box 16)
          (no. 106b)
        - Escorting caravan from dock (Box 16)
          (no. 106c)
        - En route to hotel (Box 16)
          (no. 106d)
        - On Grand Hotel balcony (Box 16)
          (no. 106e)
      - Gerald Ford and Dan Musser (Box 16)
        (no. 112)
      - John Nance Garner and others (Box 16)
        (no. 113)
      - Coleman Young and others in carriage, 1987 (Box 17)
        (no. 114)
      - W. Stewart Woodfill portrait (Box 17)
        (no. 115)
      - Fitzgeralds
        - Jim and Pat Fitzgerald (Box 16)
          (no. 116a)
        - Jim and Pat Fitzgerald and Jody Powell (Box 16)
          (no. 116b)
      - Winter visitors (1), 1940s
        - Arnold dock (Box 16)
          (no. 122a)
        - Sainte Marie (Box 16)
          (no. 122b)
        - Sainte Marie arriving (Box 16)
          (no. 122c)
        - Five men in front of Sainte Marie (Box 16)
          (no. 122d)
        - Three men in front of Sainte Marie (Box 16)
          (no. 122e)
        - Five men on Grand Hotel porch (Box 16)
          (no. 122f)
      - Winter visitors (2), 1940s
        - At swimming pool (Box 16)
          (no. 122g)
        - Horse (Box 16)
          (no. 122h)
        - View of Round Island (Box 16)
          (no. 122i)
        - Woodfill house, gate closed (Box 16)
          (no. 122j)
        - Sleigh in front of Woodfill house (Box 16)
          (no. 122k)
        - Woodfill house, gate open (Box 16)
          (no. 122l)
      - Edmund Pace, headwaiter/minister, 1943 (Box 21)
        (no. 123)
      - Understudies for Spencer Tracy and Katherine Hepburn, 1946 (Box 16)
        (no. 126)
      - Dan Musser in kitchen, 1954 (Box 21)
        (no. 127)
      - World War I drum and bugle corps, October 1979 (Box 16)
        (no. 209)
      - Bill and Helen Milliken with Dan Musser (Box 17)
        (no. 213)
      - Bishop Fulton J. Sheen at Grand Hotel, September 11, 1959
        - Sheen and party (Box 16)
          (no. 222a)
        - Sheen in carriage with fort in background (Box 16)
          (no. 222b)
    - Construction
      - Grand Hotel initial construction, nearing completion in, 1887; 4 images (Box 16)
        (nos. 4a-4d)
- Audio Material, 1981-2007
  Audio Material, 1993-2000 comprises both commercial compact discs of music performed by Grand Hotel's musical staff, as well as radio advertisements promotions and interviews.
  - Bob Snyder and the Grand Hotel Orchestra
    - An Evening at the Grand Volume I, 1993 (Box 8)
    - An Evening at the Grand Volume II, undated (Box 8)
    - Amazing Grace: Sunday at the G, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Radio Spots
    - Two commercials promoting Jazz Weekend, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 8)
    - Three commercials mentioning review in Gourmet Magazine, June 1997; audio cassette tape (Box 8)
    - Three general commercials, May 27, 1998; audio cassette tape (Box 8)
    - Six general commercials, May 10, 2000; audio cassette tape (Box 8)
    - Two commercials promoting Jazz Weekend, 1999; audio CD (Box 8)
    - Three general commercials, 1999; audio CD (Box 8)
  - Promotional Giveaways
    - Bob Collins Show, WGN Radio 720, August 2, 1992; audio cassette tape (Box 8)
    - "Mackinac in the Morning", NewsRadio 790 WSGW, May 1998; audio cassette tape (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Audio cassette tapes
      - "Grand Hotel Visit", May 12-15, 1983 (Box 8)
      - "Frank Kelly at Jeff-Jack", March 10, 1984 (Box 8)
      - "The Grand Hotel" WJR, July 20, 1989 (Box 8)
      - "Michigan -- copy from client cassette master," Foote Cone & Belding, June 26, 1995 (Box 8)
      - "1995 Celebrity Golf Series" WJR, July 12, 1995; 2 audiocassettes (Box 8)
      - Dan Musser on WKHM, Jackson, Mich., May 2, 1996 (Box 8)
      - "WSGW's Grand Getaway", March 27-April 25, 1997 (Box 8)
      - "Taste Mention" WBBM, Chicago, July 6, 1997 (Box 8)
      - "Sylvain on Travel" WWJ, July 30, year unidentified (Box 8)
      - "Korab demos", undated (Box 8)
      - Wally Phillips Show WGN, August 21, year unidentified (Box 8)
      - "Grand Hotel A.V.,", undated (Box 8)
    - Microcassette tapes
      - Visa commercial (Box 8)
      - Paul Harvey (Box 8)
    - Compact discs
      - "Marathon Radio", July 3, 2001 (Box 8)
      - Paul W. Smith Show, WJR, live from Mackinac, April 28, 2004; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 8)
      - Travel Globe Radio, June 2004; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 8)
      - Grand Hotel radio commercial, WJR, August 2004 (Box 8)
      - Paul W. Smith Show, WJR, April 27, 2005 (Box 8)
      - "Travel Michigan/WJR", February 26, 2006 (Box 8)
      - "Where to Play Golf Radio Show,", February 24, 2007 (Box 8)
      - "Travel Michigan on WJR", April 22, 2007 (Box 8)
      - "Handyman Show with Glenn Haege" WJR, August 11, 2007 (Box 8)
      - "Travel America" WRMN, undated (Box 8)
      - WJR "Discover Good Food" program, 2 optical disks CDs (Box 8)
    - Unidentified digital format
      - Unidentified item from Michigan Talk Radio Network (Box 8)
- Videographic Material, 1980-2011
  Videographic Material, 1980-2011 comprises mainly tapes of television shows that featured Grand Hotel or its staff. Highlights of this series include interviews with executives and employees of the hotel, as well as videographic images of the hotel and its surroundings. Also included in this series are two commercially produced videocassettes on Mackinac Island and its history.
  - U-Matic (Box 24)
    - Bald Head Island Mini Sales Doc. (Box 24)
    - Grand Hotel (Box 24)
    - Grand Hotel 100th Birthday (4:05), May 1987 (Box 24)
    - Close-Up: Grand Hotel/100th Anniversary (9:22), July 1987 (Box 24)
    - Robinson's Inc, "1980 Resort Executive of the Year Award" (Box 24)
    - Mackinac Island (Box 24)
    - 700 Club (Mackinac Island sequence), 1981 (Box 24)
    - PM Magazine, Milwaukee 1981 Grand Hotel story, October 8, 1981; also carriage shots, October 7, 1981 (Box 24)
  - Betacam videocassette tapes
    - Michigan Travel Bureau footage of Mackinac Is, June 26, 1997 (Box 24)
    - Golf Michigan episode on Grand Hotel, May 1998 (Box 24)
  - VHS videocassettes
    - American Magazine Show 94104, Grand Hotel Segment (Box 9)
      (video #1)
    - Chicago Live, An Interview with Dan Musser (Box 9)
      (video #2)
    - Consumer Program, Grand Hotel (Box 9)
      (video #3)
    - Fork in the Road, Episode 11 (Grand Hotel kitchen tour), January 19, 2003 (Box 9)
      (video #4)
    - Golf Michigan, undated (Box 9)
      (video #5)
    - Good Morning America, "In Search of America" series segment on Michigan, with short interview with Dan Musser III, undated (Box 9)
      (video #6)
    - Grand Hotel (Box 9)
      (video #7)
    - Grand Hotel (Box 9)
      (video #8)
    - Grand Hotel Slideshow Sample, Balthazar Korab Ltd. Slideshow Vignettes (Box 9)
      (video #9)
    - Grand Hotel Tourism in Eastern Upper Peninsula CCSS-Rudyard (Box 9)
      (video #10)
    - WNEM Golf series spot on Woods course, with brief interview clips with course designer Jerry Matthew, undated (Box 9)
      (video #11)
    - Great Lakes Ports O'Call Episode #201 featuring Mackinac Is, 2001 (Box 9)
      (video #12)
    - Eddie Jaye, One of America's Foremost Convention/Banquet Comedy Entertainers (Box 9)
      (video #13)
    - QVC Local, Michigan Week Spots, with spot on Grand Hotel, undated (Box 9)
      (video #14)
    - State of Michigan, "Sesquicentennial Program" (Box 9)
      (video #15)
    - Travel Writers Conference (Box 9)
      (video #16)
    - Michigan Magazine, Episodes #349 and #350, 1992; 2 videocassettes (Box 9)
      (includes interview with Grand Hotel Vice President Anthony Smith, and features the Traveling Classroom, a 7th-grade history program whose students stayed at Grand Hote)
      (videos 17 & 18)
    - Robinson's Inc, "1980 Resort Executive of the Year Award" (Box 10)
      (video #19)
    - Grand Hotel: Carleton Varney interview, May 1983 (Box 10)
      (video #20)
    - Italian TV Looks at Mackinac Is, 1983 (Box 10)
      (in Italian with voice over English by W.T. Rabe)
      (video #21)
    - The Resort Committee of the American Hotel & Motel Association, 1984 (Box 10)
      (video #22)
    - Grand Hotel Gardens & Stone Skipping Tournament, Detroit, July 4, 1985 (Box 10)
      (video #23)
    - Interview with Dan Musser, Margaret Kappa, Grand Hotel Exterior Shot "The Way Ahead" (Box 10)
      (video #24)
    - Klingman's Great Summer Sale, 1986 (Box 10)
      (video #25)
    - Michigan Forward, February 20, 1987 (Box 10)
      (video #26)
    - Walk Michigan '86, TV Version, May 28, 1987 (Box 10)
      (video #27)
    - Colony Interconnects, Commercial, July-August 1987 (Box 10)
      (video #28)
    - Grand 100 Capitol Club, 1987 (Box 10)
      (video #29)
    - Int. Fin. Planning, Summer Extravaganza, 1988 (Box 10)
      (video #30)
    - Michigan Travel Bureau, Commercials (I & II), S8-15, Summer 1988 (Box 10)
      (video #31)
    - When the Horses Leave: Metamorphosis at Mackinac, Winter on Mackinac, 1988 (Box 10)
      (Produced for PBS by Ch. 13, Marquette, Michigan)
      (video #32)
    - Winter on Mackinac Is, 1988 (Box 10)
      3 or 4 parts, ea 5 min, by Mort Crim, Channel IV, Detroit
      (video #33)
    - Grand Hotel, NBC Today Show, August 4, 1989 (Box 10)
      (video #34)
    - Grand Hotel on NBC-TV's "Today" show, August 4, 1989 (Box 15)
      (video #35)
    - Mackinac Island News Coverage, WDIV -- TV 4 News/Detroit, May 11, 1990 (Box 15)
      (video #36)
    - Going Our Way, TNN, August 1992 (Box 15)
      (video #37)
    - Consumer Travel Reports, Week of, October 25, 1993 (Box 15)
      (video #38)
    - Small Business Journal Program III, September 1994 (Box 15)
      (includes video from the Small Business Association Summer convention at Grand Hotel)
      (video #39)
    - "Grand Re-Opening" segment on WDIV news, May 12, 1995 (Box 15)
      (includes interviews with Dan Musser III and Charles Williams, longest-term hotel employee)
      (video #40)
    - WZZM ABC-13 "The Morning News" from Mackinac, July 8, 1996 (Box 15)
      (morning news hosts broadcast from Grand Hotel's porch; includes interview with chef Anthony Smith)
      (video #41)
    - Mackinac Island, Grand Hotel Summer Tourism, 1996 (Box 15)
      (video #42)
    - Grand Hotel, Today, NBC-TV Network, July 9, 1997 (Box 15)
      (video #43)
    - Channel 7 Spotlight on the News: The Grand Old Is, 1997 (Box 15)
      (includes panel-style interview with Dan Musser III, Mimi Musser, Marlee Musser, and Margaret Doud, Mayor of Mackinac Island)
      (video #44)
    - American Express / A&E Television America's Castles promotion, 1998 (Box 15)
      (video #45)
    - Commercial that ran during Golf Michigan, March 9, 2001 (Box 15)
      (tape includes entire episode of show, which was sponsored by Grand Hotel)
      (video #46)
    - "Mackinac Island: A 600 Year History", 2000 (Box 15)
      (written and produced by Al and Dave Eicher)
      (video #47)
    - Good Day Wisconsin segment "Cooking with Amy", July 2000 (Box 15)
      (cooking segment featuring Grand Hotel Chef Hans Burtsher)
      (video #48)
    - WILX TV 10 news story on Somewhere in Time event, 2002 (Box 15)
      (includes interview with Jane Seymour at Grand Hotel)
      (video #49)
    - Public Places, Private Spaces with Nancy Glass, Episode 110, December 4, 2002 (Box 15)
      (features designs by Carleton Varney, including Grand Hotel)
      (video #50)
    - Weekend Explorer, episode on Mackinac Is, 2004 (Box 15)
      (video #51)
    - Best of the Midwest with Dan Kaercher, #102 (Iowa Public Television Program), 26:16 min. (Box 15)
    - Jane Seymour Mackinac Island Home Collection, 2:18 min. (Box 15)
    - Media Meet #615: Travel (Box 15)
    - NBC News: Mackinac Island (Box 15)
    - Hospitality Industry (Box 15)
  - DVD Videos, 10 optical disks DVDs
    - Michigan Political History Society tour given by Dan Musser, August 25, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Mackinac Policy Conference (WXYZ, Spotlight on the News), 2006 (Box 15)
    - Little People, Big World, Episode 425 "Somewhere in Time", November 13, 2008 (Box 15)
    - An Interview with R.D. Musser, conducted by Bill Ballenger, Michigan Political History Society, December 17, 2009 (Box 15)
    - Michigan Golf Live, Grand Hotel Episode #205 (Box 15)
    - Best of the Midwest with Dan Kaercher, 2005 (Box 15)
    - Fox 2 Detroit, News coverage of Grand Hotel on Mackinac Is, April 30, 2009; May 1, 2009 (Box 15)
    - Mackinac Island: Mecca of the Midwest, May 28, 2006 (Box 15)
      (Chicago public television program; taped from the television)
    - Detroit Regional Chamber, 2008 (Box 15)
    - Maranda Where You Live, Mackinac Island show, May 21, 2011 (Box 15)